Guide to the Louise Morgan and Otto Theis Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Everyman (London: 1929); Outlook (London: 1898); African American authors; British literature -- 20th Century; Child health services -- Great Britain; Exercise therapy -- Great Britain; Mental illness; Public health -- Great Britain; Publishers and publishing -- Great Britain; Great Britain -- Social conditions -- 1933-1945; Reviews (documents); Authors; Literary agents; Poets; H. D. (Hilda Doolittle), 1886-1961; Alexander, F. Matthias (Frederick Matthias), 1869-1955; Balderston, John L. (John Lloyd), 1889-1954; Balderston, Marion; Bloomfield, Paul, 1898-; Bowes-Lyon, Lilian Helen, 1895-1949; Brodribb, Sylvia; Bryher, 1894-1983; Budberg, Moura, 1892-1974; Cameron, Carin Wander; Cameron, William, 1905-; Clifton, Vivian; Cunard, Nancy, 1896-1965; Edgerton, Gladys; Ellerman, J. R. (John Reeves), 1909-1973; Evans, Donald, 1884-1921; Freud, Anna, 1895-1982; Grant, Doris; Holtzmann, Fanny E. (Fanny Ellen), 1903-1980; Jameson, Storm, 1891-1986; Kay-Scott, C., 1879-1960; Lynd, Sylvia; Mannin, Ethel, 1900-1984; Mansel, Freda; Masefield, John, 1878-1967; McAlmon, Robert, 1896-1956; Merton, Owen, 1887-1931; Metcalf, John, 1891-; Morgan, Louise; Padmore, George, 1902-1959; Palmer, Herbert E. (Herbert Edward), 1880-1961; Patmore, Brigit; Powell-Edwards, Tony; Rankin, Rhondda; Rathbone, Irene, 1892-1980; Richardson, Dorothy M. (Dorothy Miller), 1873-1957; Roberts, Joanna; Royde-Smith, Naomi, 1875-1964; Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970; Sanderson, Averil, Lady; Scott, Evelyn, 1893-1963; Steen, Marguerite, 1894-; Sutherland, Millicent, Duchess of, 1867-1955; Sutton, Eric; Swing, Betty Gram, 1893-1969; Swing, Raymond, 1887-1968; Swinnerton, Frank, 1884-1982; Theis, O. F. (Otto Frederick), 1881-; Wallace, Ethel; Waller, Madge; Young, A. P.
- Correspondence, 1902-83; Series I; 8.25; (20 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, fills Boxes 1-20. It is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and then chronologically. Separate listings have been given for each correspondent with three or more letters. Individuals with one or two letters have been placed in "Letter" general files. Files include letters to and some letters from Louise Morgan or Otto Theis. There is also some third party correspondence. Undated and miscellaneous material has been placed at the end of each correspondent's file. Unidentified correspondence is found in Box 20, folders 443-46.
  - Dealer's catalog, [1986] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Additional information about the collection, [1986] (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - "A" general, 1926-61 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    Includes: Lord Harold Acton, David Astor
  - Aaronson, Betty, 1942-45 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aaumsted, Elling, ca. 1929-31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adams, H. P., 1891-55 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alberry, Jessica, 1948-61 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Albrand, Martha
  - Aldington, Richard, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Box 9, folders 186-87
  - Aldrich, Winthrop, 1943-44 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Allen, Joan, Lady, 1943-50 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Allen, Polly
  - Allison, Cyril, 1954-62 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Allison, Veronica
  - Andrews, Esther, 1922-23 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Angell, Norman, 1933-36 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ashby, Margery Corbett
    See: Box 26, folder 646
  - Astor, Nancy, 1939-59 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "B" general, 1921-58 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
    Includes: Sir Isaiah Berlin, Sir J. M. Barrie [secretary], Arnold Bax, Sir Max Beerbohm [telegram], Hilaire Belloc, Violet Bonham-Carter, E. F. Benson, John Buchan
  - Baird, Susan
    See: Box 26, folder 610
  - Balderston, John Balderston, Marion, 1919-64, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21-34)
    See also: Box 24, folders 569-70
  - Bannister, Estrid, 1936-60 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Basham, Arthur, 1932-54 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Basham, Nina
  - Bates, H. E., 1930-34 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Bawden, Edward, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Bennett, Arnold
    See: Box 26, folder 630
  - Bevan, Aneurin, 1937-46 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    See also: Box 11, folder 232; Box 24, folders 569-70
  - Bigelow, Poultney, 1938-39 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Binder, Pearl, 1938-48 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Blake, Snowdon
    See: Box 12, folders 253-54
  - Bloomfield, Paul, 1930-46 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Bolitho, Sybil, 1923-33 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Bolitho, William
  - Bowes-Lyon, Freda, 1949-62 (Box 3, Folder 44-45)
  - Bowes-Lyon, Lilian, 1935-49, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 46-50)
    See also: Box 13, folder 266; Box 14, folder 312
  - Boyle, Helen, 1947-50 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Boyle, Kay, 1925-60 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    See also: Box 11, folders 242-43
  - Brand, Rosabelle, Lady, [1920s?] (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Brandt, Zelma, 1929-62 (Box 3, Folder 54-55)
  - Brodribb, C. W., 1937-46 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Brodribb, Conant, 1941-56 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Brodribb, Sylvia, ca. 1944-61 (Box 3, Folder 58-59)
  - Brodribb, Sylvia, 1962-63 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Bryher, 1925-55 (Box 4, Folder 61-65)
    See also: Box 11, folders 242-43; Box 27, folder 659
  - Buchanan, Doris, 1952-61 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Buchanan, R. W. K.
    See: Box 4, folder 67
  - Buchannan, George, 1950-60 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Buck, Alice, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Buck, M. S., 1920 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Budberg, Moura, 1953-62, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 70-71)
  - Burdett, Osbert, 1923-32 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Burke, Thomas, 1932-33 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Burne-Jones, Edward
    See: Box 25, folder 603
  - "C" general, 1922-58 (Box 4, Folder 74-76)
    Includes: Alice Campbell, Guy Chapman, Claud Cockburn, Duff Cooper [Lord Norwich], A. E. Coppard
  - Camden, George, 1952, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Camden, Jackie
  - Cameron, Arthur, 1941, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Cameron, Carin Wander, 1950-53 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Cameron, Carin Wander, 1954-62 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Cameron, Harold, 1939-46 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Cameron, William, 1935-59, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 82-94)
    See also: Box 6, folder 108
  - Cape, Jonathan
    See: Box 11, folder 218
  - Carr, Anne, 1943-46 (Box 5, Folder 95-96)
  - Carr, E. H., 1946-51 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Carr, Joyce, 1946-61 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Carr, Martin, 1943-46 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Carr, Phyllis Carr, Rachel
  - Chi'en, Hsiao, 1942-47 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Church, Catherina, 1935-61 (Box 6, Folder 101)
  - Church, Richard
    See also: Box 28, folders 698-701
  - Clark, Arthur C., 1946-49 (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Clatworthy, [Robert], 1962 Jul 18 (Box 6, Folder 103)
    See also: Box 10, folder 202; Box 18, folder 398; Box 23, folder 531
  - Clay, Enid, 1952-60 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    See also: Box 30, folder 740
  - Clifton, Vivian, 1933-38 (Box 6, Folder 105-06)
  - Close, Major and Mrs., 1939-40 (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Conarain, Nina, 1932-60 (Box 6, Folder 108-09)
  - Constable, Theodore M.
    See: Box 21, folder 455
  - Cronin, A. J., 1931-38 (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Cutler, Marian, 1950-54 (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - "D" general, 1917-56 (Box 6, Folder 112-13)
    Includes: Walter De la Mare, Daphne Du Maurier
  - Dane, Estrid, 1945-49 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Das, Frieda Hauswith, 1933-49 (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Davies, Margaret
    See: Box 24, folder 541
  - Day, J. Wentworth, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Delderfield, R. F., 1947-50 (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Dent, Mr. and Mrs. H. R., 1931-50 (Box 6, Folder 118-19)
  - Donald, Robert, Sir
    See: Box 9, folder 166; Box 27, folder 660, 655-58
  - Doyle, Arthur Conan, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Dunbar, William
    See: Box 21, folder 471
  - "E" general, 1922-61 (Box 6, Folder 121-22)
  - Easterbrook, Laurence, 1945-46 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 926
  - Edgerton, Fannie, 1919, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Edgerton, Gladys, 1919-23 (Box 6, Folder 125-27)
  - Edgerton, Gladys, 1963-64 (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - Edib, Halide, 1929-47 (Box 7, Folder 129)
    See also: Box 30, folder 745; Oversize, Box 39, folder 927
  - Ellerman, Anne, 1929-32 (Box 7, Folder 130)
  - Ellerman, John, Sir, 1928-40 (Box 7, Folder 131)
    See also: Box 27, folder 659
  - Elliot, Bernice, 1963-67 (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - Ellis, Havelock, 1931 Jan 16 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    See also: Box 21, folder 472; Box 27, folder 659
  - Enthoven, Heda, 1941-60 (Box 7, Folder 134)
  - Ervine, St. John, 1933-36 (Box 7, Folder 135)
  - Evans, Anne, 1903-19 (Box 7, Folder 136-37)
  - Evans, William
  - Evans, Donald, 1902-05 (Box 7, Folder 138-44)
    See also: Arthur Davison Ficke Box 8, folder 157; Box 10, folder 189; Box 12, folder 262; Box 16, folders 357-61; Box 19, folders 431-34; Box 20, folder 443; Oversize, Box 39, folder 928
  - Evans, Donald, 1906-19, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 145-54)
  - Evans, Ernestine, 1936-59 (Box 8, Folder 155)
  - Ewer, Monica, 1936-49 (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - Ewer, Trilby
  - "F" general, 1921-49 (Box 8, Folder 157-58)
    Includes: E. M. Forster
  - Fairfield, Letitia, 1925-47 (Box 8, Folder 159)
  - Farjeon, Eleanor, 1933-61 (Box 8, Folder 160)
  - Farjeon, Herbert
  - Fitzgerald, F. Scott
    See: Box 24, folder 546
  - Fletcher, Luba, Lady, 1951-55 (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - Freud, Anna, 1941-58 (Box 8, Folder 162-63)
    See also: Box 23, folders 521-25
  - Freud, Sigmund
    See: Oversize, Box 39, folder 934
  - "G" general, 1931-82 (Box 8, Folder 164-65)
    Includes: Robert Gibbings
  - Garvin, J. L., 1932-33 (Box 9, Folder 166)
  - Garvin, Viola
  - Gauthier, Eva, 1925-26 (Box 9, Folder 167)
  - Gibbings, Robert
    See: Golden Cockerel Press Box 8, folder 165
  - Globe-Mermaid Association
    See: Box 13, folder 288
  - Golding, Louis, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 168)
  - Goldman, Emma
    See: Box 23, folder 536
  - Gordine, Dora, 1947, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 169)
  - Gordon, Alvin, 1933, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 170)
  - Gordon-Crotch, Martha, 1949-52 (Box 9, Folder 171)
  - Gould, Frederick J., 1930-36 (Box 9, Folder 172)
  - Graham, W. S., 1947-49 (Box 9, Folder 173)
    See also: Box 12, folder 247
  - Grant, Doris, 1950-63 (Box 9, Folder 174-75)
  - Greville, Ursula, 1925-28 (Box 9, Folder 176)
  - Griffith, Katie, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 177)
  - Griffith, Sanford, 1929-61 (Box 9, Folder 178)
  - Griffith, Valerie Courtenay, 1953-83 (Box 9, Folder 179)
  - Griffiths, H. Ernest, 1943-48 (Box 9, Folder 180)
  - Guiness, Bryan, 1935-47 (Box 9, Folder 181)
  - Gunther, Frances, 1935-59 (Box 9, Folder 182)
  - Gunther, John
  - Gutherie, Judith, 1946, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 183)
  - Gutherie, Tyrone
  - "H" general, 1904-60 (Box 9, Folder 184-85)
    Includes: Rupert Hart-Davis
  - H.D., 1926, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - Hanley, James, 1930-58 (Box 9, Folder 187)
  - Harrison, Rita
    See: Box 12, folders 264-65
  - Harwood, Dorothy, 1924-61 (Box 10, Folder 188)
  - Harwood, H. C.
  - Hawes, Millicent
    See: Box 17, folders 375-77
  - Henderson, W. N., 1903 (Box 10, Folder 189)
    See also: Box 7, folders 136-44
  - Hilton, James, 1933-34 (Box 10, Folder 190)
  - Holmes, Miss Gordon, 1942-49 (Box 10, Folder 191)
  - Holtzmann, David M., 1962 (Box 10, Folder 192)
  - Holtzmann, Fanny, 1937-62, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 193-202)
    See also: Box 11, folder 223; Box 6, folder 104; Box 18, folder 398; Francis Williams Box 18, folder 408
  - Holtzmann, Howard, 1947, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 203)
  - Hopkinson, Thomas, 1945-55 (Box 10, Folder 204)
  - Horder, Thomas, Lord, 1941-47 (Box 10, Folder 205)
    See also: Box 28, folder 697
  - Houghton, Claude, 1933-54 (Box 10, Folder 206)
  - Howe, Olga, 1933-62 (Box 10, Folder 207)
  - Hubble, Grace, 1948-50 (Box 10, Folder 208)
  - Hunt, Eunice, 1925-40 (Box 10, Folder 209)
  - Hunt, Frazier
    See also: Box 21, folder 472
  - Hunter, Anne Morgan, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 210)
  - "I" general, 1933, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 211)
  - "J" general, 1930-57 (Box 10, Folder 212-13)
  - Jameson, Egon, 1941-53 (Box 10, Folder 214)
  - Jameson, Storm, 1931-41 (Box 11, Folder 215-16)
    See also: Box 15, folders 323-28
  - Jesse, Fryn Tennyson, 1945-46 (Box 11, Folder 217)
  - Jonathan Cape Ltd., 1934-49 (Box 11, Folder 218)
    See also: Box 30, folder 729
  - Jones, Dorothy Rouse, 1940-57 (Box 11, Folder 219)
  - "K" general, 1931-56 (Box 11, Folder 220-21)
  - Kerr, John Graham, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 222)
  - Kevles, Bettyann Holtzmann, 1958-62 (Box 11, Folder 223)
    See also: Box 10, folders 193-202
  - King, Vivian, 1938-52 (Box 11, Folder 224)
    See also: Box 14, folders 314-15
  - Knowles, Christine, 1946-50 (Box 11, Folder 225)
  - Koch, Sigmond, 1952-53 (Box 11, Folder 226)
  - "L" general, 1917-60 (Box 11, Folder 227-28)
    Includes: John Lehmann, Wyndham Lewis, Eric Linklater
  - Lamude, F. J., 1931-61 (Box 11, Folder 229)
  - Lane, Margaret, 1936-58 (Box 11, Folder 230)
  - Lawrence, Pamela
    See: Box 6, folder 104; Box 10, folder 202; Box 18, folder 398; Box 23, folder 531
  - Layton, T. B., 1942-53 (Box 11, Folder 231)
  - Lee, Jennie, 1940-63 (Box 11, Folder 232)
    See also: Box 2, folder 39; Box 24, folders 569-70
  - Leslie, Shane, 1923-51 (Box 11, Folder 233)
  - Lewis, Sinclair, 1923, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 234)
  - Longmoor, Gwen, 1940-55 (Box 11, Folder 235)
  - Lowndes, Marie Belloc, 1930-31 (Box 11, Folder 236)
  - Lowenfeld, Margaret, 1944-45 (Box 11, Folder 237)
  - Lynd, Sylvia, 1930-58 (Box 11, Folder 238-39)
  - "M" general, 1922-58 (Box 11, Folder 240-41)
    Includes: Alice Meynell, John Middleton Murry, C. K. Munro
  - McAlmon, Robert, 1926-59 (Box 11, Folder 242-43)
    See also: Box 4, folders 61-66; Box 12, folders 250-52; Box 21, folder 472; Box 27, folder 659; Box 31, folder 769
  - Macaulay, Rose, 1920-58 (Box 12, Folder 244)
    See also: Box 27, folder 652
  - McFall, David, 1947, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 245)
  - Mackenzie, Compton, Sir, 1930-33 (Box 12, Folder 246)
  - MacLeod, Vivienne Koch, 1947-59 (Box 12, Folder 247)
    See also: Box 11, folder 226
  - Malcolm, Beatrice, 1931-35 (Box 12, Folder 248-49)
    See also: Box 14, folders 301-09
  - Mannin, Ethel, 1933-51 (Box 12, Folder 250-52)
    See also: Box 25, folder 596
  - Mansel, Freda, 1935-40 (Box 12, Folder 253-54)
  - Markham, Violet, 1940-46 (Box 12, Folder 255)
  - Marlowe, David, 1944-52 (Box 12, Folder 256)
  - Marston, Alvan T.
    See: Box 21, folder 449
  - Masefield, John, 1931-62 (Box 12, Folder 257-59)
  - Maugham, W. Somerset, 1961, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 260)
  - Mead, Jane, 1937-57 (Box 12, Folder 261)
    See also: Box 26, folder 621
  - Menard, Charles, 1903 (Box 12, Folder 262)
    See also: Box 7, folders 136-44; Box 16, folders 357-61; Box 20, folder 443
  - Montgomery, Lady, 1944-61 (Box 12, Folder 263)
  - Moore, George
    See: Box 21, folder 454
  - Morgan, Rita, 1945-60 (Box 12, Folder 264-65)
  - Mott, Elizabeth, 1947-57 (Box 13, Folder 266)
    See also: Box 21, folder 466
  - Mottram, R. H., 1930 (Box 13, Folder 267)
    See also: Box 27, folder 653
  - Mountbatten, Edwina, Lady, 1940-41 (Box 13, Folder 268)
  - Mullins, Claud, 1935-60 (Box 13, Folder 269)
  - Murrow, Larry, 1930-36 (Box 13, Folder 270)
  - "N" general, 1932-48 (Box 13, Folder 271)
    Includes: Vladimir Nabokov, A. P. Nicholson
  - Neill, A. S., 1949-50 (Box 13, Folder 272)
    See also: Box 26, folder 623
  - Nesbitt, Faith, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 273)
  - Newfield, Maurice, 1942-45 (Box 13, Folder 274)
  - Newman, Audrey, 1942-45 (Box 13, Folder 275)
  - Nichols, Beverley, 1931-33 (Box 13, Folder 276)
  - Norman, Odette, 1940-54 (Box 13, Folder 277)
    See also: Box 14, folders 301-309
  - Norton, Eleanor, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 278)
  - Notestein, Wallace, 1948-57 (Box 13, Folder 279)
  - "O" general, 1928-45 (Box 13, Folder 280)
  - Odle, Rose, 1933-61 (Box 13, Folder 281-82)
  - Ogden, C. K., 1939-44 (Box 13, Folder 283)
    See also: Box 21, folder 455
  - Oldfield, Josiah, 1931-49 (Box 13, Folder 284)
  - O'Sullivan, Richard, 1926-33 (Box 13, Folder 285)
  - Oved, Mosheh, 1926-52 (Box 13, Folder 286)
  - Oved, Sa[b], 1931-58 (Box 13, Folder 287)
  - Owlett, F. C., 1936-38 (Box 13, Folder 288)
  - "P" general, 1931-44 (Box 13, Folder 289-90)
    Includes: Eric Partridge
  - Padmore, George, 1935-39 (Box 13, Folder 291-92)
  - Palmer, Herbert Edward, 1923-58, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 293-297)
  - Pant, Apa B, Raja of Aundh, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 298)
  - Paterson, T. T., 1939-50 (Box 14, Folder 299)
    See also: Box 21, folder 446
  - Patmore, Brigit, 1927-52 (Box 14, Folder 300)
  - Patmore, Derek
  - Peckham Experiment
    See: Box 25, folders 582-85
  - Pember, Evelyn, 1928-63, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 301-09)
    See also: Box 12, folders 248-49; Box 13, folder 277
  - Pennyman, Ruth, 1945, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 310)
  - Philips, Georgiana, 1939-54 (Box 14, Folder 311)
  - Plomer, William, 1932-58 (Box 14, Folder 312)
  - Poliakoff, Olga
    See: Box 10, folder 207
  - Porter, Katherine Anne
    See: Box 11, folders 242-43
  - Pound, Ezra
    See: Box 11, folders 242-43; Box 13, folder 290
  - Powell-Edwards, Tony (Ivor), 1935-52 (Box 14, Folder 313-14)
    See also: Box 11, folder 224
  - Pritchett, V. S., 1932, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 315)
  - Purdom, C. B., 1955 (Box 14, Folder 316)
    See also: Box 27, folders 655-58, 659
  - Puxley, Zoe, 1945, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 317)
  - "R" general, 1923-54 (Box 15, Folder 318-19)
    Includes: Eslanda Goode Robeson
  - Rankin, Rhondda, 1934-48 (Box 15, Folder 320-21)
  - Ratcliff, Jim, 1954-57 (Box 15, Folder 322)
  - Rathbone, Irene, 1940-64 (Box 15, Folder 323-28)
  - Reading, Marchioness of, 1933-51 (Box 15, Folder 329)
  - Rhodes, Cecil
    See: Box 26, folder 612
  - Richardson, Dorothy, 1926-52 (Box 15, Folder 330-31)
    See also: Box 11, 242-43; Box 13, folders 281-82;Box 21, folder 472; Box 27, folder 659
  - Ridge, Lola, 1920, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 332)
  - Roberts, Joanna, 1943-59 (Box 15, Folder 333-34)
  - Robertson, W. Graham, 1931-33 (Box 15, Folder 335)
  - Robinson, E. A., 1920-24 (Box 15, Folder 336)
  - Rodker, John, 1930-34 (Box 15, Folder 337)
  - Ross, Charles, Sir, 1919-22 (Box 15, Folder 338)
  - Royde-Smith, Naomi, 1925-33 (Box 15, Folder 339-340)
  - Russell, Alys, 1948-51 (Box 16, Folder 341)
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1923, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 342)
  - Russell, Dora, 1924-59 (Box 16, Folder 343)
  - "S" general, 1931-57 (Box 16, Folder 344-45)
    Includes: George Saintsbury, George Santayana, Siegfried Sassoon, Ronald Searle, C. P. Snow (and letter to), Stanley Spencer, John Stratchey
  - Sanderson, Averil, Lady, 1933-58 (Box 16, Folder 346-48)
  - Sandison, Helen C., 1936-59 (Box 16, Folder 349)
  - Schnitzler, Arthur, 1920, 1922 (Box 16, Folder 350)
  - Schulberg, Ad, 1934-45 (Box 16, Folder 351)
  - Schulberg, Barbara, 1949-52 (Box 16, Folder 352)
  - Schulberg, Sonya, 1936-39 (Box 16, Folder 353)
  - Sedgwick, Anne Douglas
    See: Box 16, folder 354
  - Segal, Arthur Segal, Ernestine
    See: Box 21, folder 451
  - Selincourt, Anne de, 1931 (Box 16, Folder 354)
  - Selincourt, Hugh de, 1932, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 355)
  - Settle, Alison, 1947-50 (Box 16, Folder 356)
  - Shapleigh, Norwald, 1903-04, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 357-61)
    See also: Box 7, folders 136-44; Box 12, folder 262; Box 20, folder 443
  - Sharp, Clifford, 1931-32 (Box 17, Folder 362)
  - Sheridan, Claire, 1936-51 (Box 17, Folder 363)
  - Sheridan, Mary, 1950-55 (Box 17, Folder 364)
    See also: Box 22, folder 510
  - Soal, S. G., 1948-50 (Box 17, Folder 365)
  - Somerville, Mary, 1946-63 (Box 17, Folder 366)
  - Spender, Mary, 1938-42 (Box 17, Folder 367)
  - Steen, Marguerite, 1932-42, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 368-72)
  - Strachan, W. J., 1948-53 (Box 17, Folder 373)
  - Sturge, Anne, 1934-39 (Box 17, Folder 374)
  - Sturge, Lewis
  - Sullivan, J. M.
    See: Box 22, folder 505
  - Sutherland, Millicent (Hawes), Duchess of, 1922-28 (Box 17, Folder 375-77)
  - Sutton, Eric, 1924-45, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 378-80)
  - Swing, Betty, 1923-36 (Box 17, Folder 381-82)
  - Swing, Betty, 1937-51,n.d. (Box 18, Folder 383-86)
  - Swing, Raymond, 1924-62 (Box 18, Folder 387-89)
  - Swing, Peter, 1932-40 (Box 18, Folder 390)
  - Swing, Sally
  - Swinnerton, Frank, 1931-38 (Box 18, Folder 391-392)
    See also: Box 27, folder 654
  - Symons, Arthur, 1923-33 (Box 18, Folder 393)
  - "T" general, 1926-48 (Box 18, Folder 394-95)
    Includes: Ivor Thomas
  - Temple, Ann, 1943, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 396)
  - Theis, Grover C., 1916-19 (Box 18, Folder 397)
  - Theis, Harry, 1903-56 (Box 18, Folder 398)
  - Theis, Michael, ca. 1962-83 (Box 18, Folder 399)
    See also: Box 6, folder 104; Box 18, folder 398; Box 23, folder 531
  - Theis, Sophia, 1955-56 (Box 18, Folder 400)
  - Tilby, A. Wyatt, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 401)
    See also: Box 27, folders 655-58
  - Tomalin, Miles, 1949, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 402)
  - Travers, Ben, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 403)
  - "U" general, 1938-62 (Box 18, Folder 404)
  - "V" general, 1932-52 (Box 18, Folder 405)
  - Vale, Edmond, 1939-48 (Box 18, Folder 406)
  - Vale, Ruth
  - Vaughan, Janet, 1934-51 (Box 18, Folder 407)
  - "W" general, 1921-61 (Box 18, Folder 408-09)
    Includes: Hugh Walpole, Alec Waugh, Virginia Woolf
  - Waldman, Hazel, 1928-29, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 410-12)
  - Waldman, Milton, 1926-51 (Box 19, Folder 413)
  - Waldman, Peggy
  - Wallace, Ethel, 1922-23 (Box 19, Folder 414-17)
  - Waller, Madge, 1937-61 (Box 19, Folder 418-22)
  - Warner, Dorothy, 1931-32 (Box 19, Folder 423)
  - Warner, Oliver
  - Warner, Sylvia Townsend, 1961-62 (Box 19, Folder 424)
  - Warren, Henry, 1932, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 425)
  - West, Rebecca, Dame, 1951, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 426)
  - Wied, K., 1938-39 (Box 19, Folder 427)
    See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 929
  - Wilkinson, Ellen, 1946, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 428)
  - Wilkinson, Mona, 1931-63 (Box 19, Folder 429)
  - Williams, Juliet Rhys, 1934-50 (Box 19, Folder 430)
  - Windmill Press
    See: Arnold Gyde Box 8, folder 165
  - Winslow, Leah, 1912-32 (Box 19, Folder 431-34)
  - Wolfe, Humbert, 1923-38 (Box 20, Folder 435)
  - Woollcombe, Joan, 1936-55 (Box 20, Folder 436)
  - "Y" general, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 437)
  - Young, A. P., 1947-48 (Box 20, Folder 438-39)
  - Young, Alan, 1943-46 (Box 20, Folder 440)
  - Young, J. Z., 1949-50 (Box 20, Folder 441)
    See also: Box 29, folders 712-14
  - "Z" general, 1913 (Box 20, Folder 442)
    Includes: Stefan Zweig
    - Unidentified
      - [?], Claude, 1904 (Box 20, Folder 443)
        See also: Box 7, folders 136-44; Box 16, folder 262; Box 16, folders 355-59
      - Po[?], Juliet Stuart, 1922-23 (Box 20, Folder 444)
      - R[?], Mike, 1923-24 (Box 20, Folder 445)
      - General, 1923-62 (Box 20, Folder 446)
- Subject Files, 1917-65; Series II; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  Series II, Subject Files, fills Boxes 21-26, and contains writings and drawings by individuals; articles, notes, and correspondence about individuals; photographs; and third person and business correspondence. The series is arranged alphabetically by personal name or subject. If there are multiple folders or only one kind of material, the material type is indicated.
  - Alexander, Melinda, 1934, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 447)
  - Anderson, H. Foster (Box 21, Folder 448)
  - Anthropology: articles, 1948, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 449)
  - Architectural Review: correspondence, 1946 Feb 19 (Box 21, Folder 450)
  - Arthur Segal's Painting School: correspondence, 1942-58 (Box 21, Folder 451)
  - Aura: News Chronicle story, 1935-37 (Box 21, Folder 452)
  - Bachelor Motherhood League, 1946, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 453)
  - Balderston, John: The Brook Kerith, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 454)
  - Basic English: pamphlets, ca. 1930-50 (Box 21, Folder 455)
  - Basic Movement, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 456)
  - Bates, H. E., 1930-31 (Box 21, Folder 457)
  - Birrell, Augustine: "Josephus (That Learned Jew)", 1932, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 458)
  - Bloomfield, Paul: drawings, 1932, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 459)
  - Bone, David, Sir: obituary, 1959 Mar 18 (Box 21, Folder 460)
  - Botibol, Jenetta, 1947, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 461)